EUJEONG CHOI

LINGUIST | AI DATA BUILDING



+82 10-3595-0608

eujeonglesleychoi@gmail.com

Seoul, South Korea

https://bethegiver.github.io/

PROFILE

I am an enthusiast of Data-Centric Al.

During the last 5 years, I invested in creating robust and trustworthy **NLP Datasets** with a reliable **Data Pipeline**. In this process, I have taken part in both academic and industrial applications, and am especially interested in **optimizing data production without compromising its quality**.

SKILLS

- English & Korean Bilingual
- ML Data Scheme Generation
- Annotation Guideline & Instruction
- In-house Annotator Management
- Fluent in: Python, Spreadsheet
- Experienced in: Github, Label Studios

EXPERIENCE

DATA MANAGER

Jul 2021 - Present

Upstage (https://upstage.ai/)

- Built two main NLP Datasets (with in-house annotators)
 - Involved Domain: Movie, Beauty Review & Query
- Devised a Data Schema applicable to the model & Managed annotators
- Took part in automating & accelerating the Data Production Pipeline

AI LANGUAGE TECH LABS INTERN

Apr 2020 - Oct 2020

SK Telecom (https://www.skt.ai/kr/)

• Organized the training data for Chatbot training and validation

ASSISTANT RESEARCHER AT KOREA UNI. Mar 2019 - Jun 2020

AWARDS

TOXIC COMMENT PREDICTION & COLLECTION SERVICE

Korean Language Information Processing System Competition 2020

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF LINGUISTICS & COMPUTER SCIENCE (LB&C)

Korea University

2017-2022

PUBLICATIONS

HCI PROJECT: HUMAN-LIKE CHATBOT AGENTS

[1] Evaluating How Users Game and Display Conversation with Human-Like Agents

CODI@Coling 2022

[2] Assessing How Users Display Self-Disclosure and Authenticity in Conversation with Human-Like Agents: A Case Study of Luda Lee

AACL-IJCNLP 2022